Guide to the Norman D. Anderson Collection on Ferris Wheels and Related Materials
Norman D. Anderson Collection on Ferris Wheels and Related Materials
circa 1890 - 2014
Anderson Norman D.
MC 00432
The Norman D. Anderson Collection on FerrisWheels and Related Materials contains manuscript materials, newsletters, research files, photographs, postcards, and publications on Ferris wheels, amusement parks, and related subjects. The primary subject of the collection is the Ferris wheel. While the focus of the material is the Ferris wheel, there is also information relating to the history of amusement parks, amusement park preservation (or lack thereof), the amusement manufacturing industry and workers in the industry, as well as other material. Included are photographs and material about the Columbian Exposition in Chicago in 1893, as well as other World's Fairs.
Dr. Norman D. Anderson is a Professor Emeritus of Science Education at North Carolina State University. In 1994 he retired after 31 years of teaching at North Carolina State University. He is a collector of materials on Ferris wheels and an ardent researcher of the Ferris wheel. Anderson authored the book Ferris Wheels: An Illustrated History, published in 1992, and he is coauthor of the 1983 children's book, Ferris Wheels as well as several science books for children. Dr. Norman Anderson produced and edited the "Ferris Wheel News."
22.5 linear feet
North Carolina State University Libraries, Special Collections Research Center
Gift of Norman D. Anderson, 2011 (Accession 2011.0273) and 2012 (Accessions 2012.0061, 2012.0185, and 2012.0207)
The collection is organized into four series: Publications, Research Files, Photographs and Images, and Ephemera.
Dr. Norman D. Anderson is a Professor Emeritus of Science Education at North Carolina State University. In 1994 he retired after 31 years of teaching at North Carolina State University. He is a collector of materials on Ferris wheels and an ardent researcher of the Ferris wheel. Anderson authored the book Ferris Wheels: An Illustrated History, published in 1992, and he is coauthor of the 1983 children's book, Ferris Wheels as well as several science books for children. Dr. Norman Anderson produced and edited the "Ferris Wheel News." In 1994 he retired after 31 years of teaching at North Carolina State University. He is the author of a series of science textbooks for junior high school students. In 1992 he received the NCSU Libraries Faculty Award.
This collection contains manuscript materials, newsletters research files, photographs, postcards, and publications on Ferris Wheels, amusement parks, and related subjects. The primary subject of the collection is the Ferris wheel. While the focus of the material is the Ferris wheel, there is also information relating to the history of amusement parks, amusement park preservation (or lack thereof), the amusement manufacturing industry and workers in the industry, as well as other material. Of particular interest to researchers will be the photographic collection and the material available on the Columbian Exposition in Chicago, as well as on other World's Fairs.
Columbian Exposition; Fried Frederick; Dahlinger Fred; Chew Mike; Fukui Yuko; Eli Bridge Company; Anderson Norman D.; Braithwaite Paul; Architecture; Amusement parks; Amusement park owners; Ferris wheels; Amusement rides; Patents
- Publications
  This series contains many of the publications present in the Norman D. Anderson Collection on Ferris Wheels and Related Materials. The most numerous publications include those of the Eli Bridge Company, the Illinois-based Ferris wheel and amusement ride manufacturer, and the Amusement Park Journal. Anderson's "Ferris Wheel News" is included under Research Files, as the publication is closely related to Anderson's extensive research on Ferris wheels. Other publications may also be found in the Research Files.
  - Amusement Park Journals, 1916-1970
    - The Optimist, 1916-1925
      Issues from 1918 contain some pieces related to the war, particularly in the February 1918 issue, which includes an article on Big Eli employees involved in the military.
      - The Optimist, 1916-1918
        - The Optimist, February 1916 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - The Optimist, March 1916 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - The Optimist, July 1916 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - The Optimist, August 1916 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - The Optimist, March 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - The Optimist, May 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - The Optimist, June 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - The Optimist, July 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - The Optimist, August 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - The Optimist, September 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - The Optimist, October 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - The Optimist, November 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - The Optimist, December 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - The Optimist, February 1918 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - The Optimist, April 1918 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - The Optimist, May 1918 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - The Optimist, June 1918 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - The Optimist, September-October 1918 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - The Optimist, November-December 1918 (Box 1, Folder 3)
          This edition contains information regarding the end of World War I and a frontispiece discussing the difficulties of the magazine (including paper shortages) during wartime.
      - The Optimist, 1919
        - The Optimist, June 1919 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - The Optimist, October 1919 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - The Optimist, November 1919 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - The Optimist, 1920
        - The Optimist, January 1920 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - The Optimist, 1921
        - The Optimist, January 1921 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - The Optimist, February 1921 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - The Optimist, March 1921 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - The Optimist, April 1921 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - The Optimist, May 1921 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - The Optimist, June 1921 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - The Optimist, July 1921 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - The Optimist, August 1921 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - The Optimist, September 1921 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - The Optimist, October 1921 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - The Optimist, 1922
        - The Optimist, March 1922 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - The Optimist, April 1922 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - The Optimist, July 1922 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - The Optimist, 1923
        - The Optimist, January 1923 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        - The Optimist, February 1923 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        - The Optimist, March 1923 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        - The Optimist, May 1923 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        - The Optimist, July 1923 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        - The Optimist, August 1923 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - The Optimist, 1924
        - The Optimist, February 1924 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - The Optimist, March 1924 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - The Optimist, April 1924 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - The Optimist, May 1924 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - The Optimist, June 1924 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - The Optimist, August 1924 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - The Optimist, September 1924 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - The Optimist, October 1924 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - The Optimist, November 1924 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - The Optimist, December 1924 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - The Optimist, 1925
        - The Optimist, Volume 10, January-December 1925 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Big Eli News, 1926-1993
      - Volumes 11-12, 1926-1927
        - Big Eli News, Volume 11, February 1926 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 11, April 1926 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 11, June 1926 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 11, August 1926 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 11, September 1926 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 11, October 1926 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 11, November 1926 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 11, December 1926 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 12, 1927; 1927 1927 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Volume 13, 1928
        - Big Eli News, Volume 13, February 1928 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 13, March 1928 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 13, April 1928 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 13, May 1928 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 13, June 1928 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 13, July 1928 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 13, August 1928 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 13, September 1928 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 13, October 1928 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 13, November 1928 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 13, December 1928 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Volume 14, 1929
        - Big Eli News, Volume 14, January 1929 (Box 2, Folder 2)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 14, March 1929 (Box 2, Folder 2)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 14, April 1929 (Box 2, Folder 2)
        - Big Eli New s, Volume 14, May 1929 (Box 2, Folder 2)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 14, June 1929 (Box 2, Folder 2)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 14, July 1929 (Box 2, Folder 2)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 14, August 1929 (Box 2, Folder 2)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 14, October 1929 (Box 2, Folder 2)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 14, November 1929 (Box 2, Folder 2)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 14, December 1929 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Volumes 15-42, 1930-1957
        - Big Eli News, Volume 15, 1930; 1930 1930 (Box 2, Folder 3)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 16, 1931; 1931 1931 (Box 2, Folder 4)
        - Big Eli News, Volumes 17-18, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 5)
        - Big Eli News ,Volumes 19-20, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 6)
        - Big Eli News, Volumes 21-22, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 7)
        - Big Eli News, Volumes 23-24, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        - Big Eli News, Volumes 25-26, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 2)
        - Big Eli News, Volumes 27-28, 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 3)
        - Big Eli News, Volumes 29-30, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 4)
        - Big Eli News, Volumes 31-32, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 5)
        - Big Eli News, Volumes 33-34, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 6)
        - Big Eli News, Volumes 35-36, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 7)
        - Big Eli News, Volumes 37-38, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 8)
        - Big Eli News, Volumes 39-40, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 1)
        - Big Eli News, Volumes 41-42, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Volume 43, 1958; 1958 1958
        - Big Eli News, Volume 43, Number 1, January-February 1958; 1958 1958 (Box 4, Folder 3)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 43, Number 2, March-April 1958; 1958 1958 (Box 4, Folder 3)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 43, Number 3, May-June 1958; 1958 1958 (Box 4, Folder 3)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 43, Number 4, July-August 1958 (Box 4, Folder 3)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 43, Number 5, September-October 1958; 1958 1958 (Box 4, Folder 3)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 43, Number 6, November-December 1958; 1958 1958 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Volume 44, 1959; 1959 1959
        - Big Eli News, Volume 44, Number 1, January-February 1959; 1959 1959 (Box 4, Folder 4)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 44, Number 2, March-April 1959; 1959 1959 (Box 4, Folder 4)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 44, Number 3, May-June 1959; 1959 1959 (Box 4, Folder 4)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 44, Number 4, July-August 1959; 1959 1959 (Box 4, Folder 4)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 44, Number 5, September-October 1959; 1959 1959 (Box 4, Folder 4)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 44, Number 6, November-December 1959; 1959 1959 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Volume 45, 1960; 1960 1960
        - Big Eli News, Volume 45, Number 1, January-February 1960; 1960 1960 (Box 4, Folder 5)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 45, Number 2, March-April 1960; 1960 1960 (Box 4, Folder 5)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 45, Number 3, May-June 1960; 1960 1960 (Box 4, Folder 5)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 45, Number 4, July-August 1960; 1960 1960 (Box 4, Folder 5)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 45, Number 5, September-October 1960; 1960 1960 (Box 4, Folder 5)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 45, Number 6, November-December 1960; 1960 1960 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Volume 46, 1961; 1961 1961
        - Big Eli News, Volume 46, Number 1, January-February 1961; 1961 1961 (Box 4, Folder 6)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 46, Number 2, March-April 1961 (Box 4, Folder 6)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 46, Number 3, May-June 1961 (Box 4, Folder 6)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 46, Number 4, July-August 1961 (Box 4, Folder 6)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 46, Number 5, September-October 1961 (Box 4, Folder 6)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 46, Number 6, November-December 1961 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Volume 47, 1962
        - Big Eli News, Volume 47, Number 1, January-February 1962 (Box 4, Folder 7)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 47, Number 2, March-April 1962 (Box 4, Folder 7)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 47, Number 3, May-June 1962 (Box 4, Folder 7)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 47, Number 4, July-August 1962 (Box 4, Folder 7)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 47, Number 5, September-October 1962 (Box 4, Folder 7)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 47, Number 6, November-December 1962 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Volume 48, 1963; 1963 1963
        - Big Eli News, Volume 48, Number 1, January-February 1963 (Box 4, Folder 8)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 48, Number 2, March-April 1963 (Box 4, Folder 8)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 48, Number 3, May-June 1963 (Box 4, Folder 8)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 48, Number 4, July-August 1963 (Box 4, Folder 8)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 48, Number 5, September-October 1963 (Box 4, Folder 8)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 48, Number 6, November-December 1963 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Volume 49, 1964; 1964 1964
        - Big Eli News, Volume 49, Number 1, January-February 1964 (Box 4, Folder 9)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 49, Number 2, March-April 1964 (Box 4, Folder 9)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 49, Number 3, May-June 1964 (Box 4, Folder 9)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 49, Number 4, July-August 1964 (Box 4, Folder 9)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 49, Number 5, September-October 1964 (Box 4, Folder 9)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 49, Number 6, November-December 1964 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Volume 50, 1965; 1965 1965
        - Big Eli News, Volume 50, Number 1, January-February 1965 (Box 4, Folder 10)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 50, Number 2, March-April 1965 (Box 4, Folder 10)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 50, Number 3, May-June 1965 (Box 4, Folder 10)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 50, Number 4, July-August 1965 (Box 4, Folder 10)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 50, Number 5, September-October 1965 (Box 4, Folder 10)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 50, Number 6, November-December 1965 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Volume 51, 1966; 1966 1966
        - Big Eli News, Volume 51, Number 1, January-March 1966 (Box 4, Folder 11)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 51, Number 2, April-June 1966 (Box 4, Folder 11)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 51, Number 3, July-September 1966 (Box 4, Folder 11)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 51, Number 4, October-December 1966 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Volume 52, 1967; 1967 1967
        - Big Eli News, Volume 52, Number 1, January-March 1967 (Box 4, Folder 12)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 52, Number 2, April-June 1967 (Box 4, Folder 12)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 52, Number 3, July-September 1967 (Box 4, Folder 12)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 52, Number 4, October-December 1967 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Volume 53, 1968; 1968 1968
        - Big Eli News, Volume 53, Number 1, Spring 1968; 1968 1968 (Box 4, Folder 13)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 53, Number 2, Summer 1968; 1968 1968 (Box 4, Folder 13)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 53, Number 3, Fall 1968; 1968 1968 (Box 4, Folder 13)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 53, Number 4, Winter 1968; 1968 1968 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Volume 54, 1969
        - Big Eli News, Volume 54, Number 2, Summer 1969 (Box 4, Folder 14)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 54, Number 3, Fall 1969; 1969 1969 (Box 4, Folder 14)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 54, Number 4, Winter 1969; 1969 1969 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Volume 55, 1970
        - Big Eli News, Volume 55, Number 1, Spring 1970; 1970 1970 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Volume 57, 1982
        - Big Eli News, Volume 57, Number 2, Fall 1982 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Volume 58, 1989
        - Big Eli News, Volume 58, Number 1, Fall 1989 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Volume 59, 1990; 1990 1990
        - Big Eli News, Volume 59, Number 2, Summer-Fall 1990 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Volume 60, 1990-1991
        - Big Eli News, Volume 60, Number 1, Spring 1990 (Box 4, Folder 19)
          This edition of Big Eli News is labeled Volume 60, Number 1 and dated Spring 1990. The label may be misprinted, as the Spring Issue of 1991 is also labeled Volume 60, Number 1.
        - Big Eli News, Volume 60, Number 1, Spring 1991 (Box 4, Folder 19)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 60, Number 2, Fall 1991 (Box 4, Folder 19)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 60, Number 3, Winter 1991; 1991 1991 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Volume 61, 1992; 1992 1992
        - Big Eli News, Volume 61, Number 1, Spring 1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 61, Number 2, Summer 1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 61, Number 3, Fall 1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 61, Number 4, Winter 1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Volume 62, 1993; 1993 1993
        - Big Eli News, Volume 62, Number 1, June 21, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 2)
        - Big Eli News, Volume 62, Number 2, Winter 1993 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Amusement Park Journal
      This subseries was kept in the original order received, as it appears that the researcher utilized a notation system in these publications.
      This material could alternately be classed under research, as it is notated by Norman Anderson and its arrangement may provide insight into his research strategies and collection management.
      - Amusement Park Journal Index, 1979-1986; 1979 1987 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Amusement Park Annual, 1979; 1979 1979 (Box 5, Folder 4)
        Written in pencil: "Amusement Park Journal Vol. 1 NO 1 1979"
      - Amusement Park Annual, Vol. 2 No. 1, March 1980; 1980 1980 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Amusement Park Journal, Vol. 2 No. 2, June, 1980; 1980 1980 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Amusement Park Journal, Vol. 3 No. 1, January 1981 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Amusement Park Journal, Vol. 3 No. 2, Summer 1981 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Amusement Park Journal, Vol. 3 No. 3, Winter 1981 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Amusement Park Journal, Vol. 4 No. 1, Spring 1982 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Amusement Park Journal, Vol 4 No. 2, Summer 1982 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Amusement Park Journal, Vol. 4 No. 3, Fall 1982 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Amusement Park Journal, Vol 4 No. 4, Winter 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Amusement Park Journal, Vol. 5 No. 2, Summer 1983 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Amusement Park Journal, Vol. 5 No. 1, Spring 1983 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Amusement Park Journal, Vol. 5 No. 3, Fall 1983 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Amusement Park Journal, Vol. 6 No. 2, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Amusement Park Journal, Vol. 7 Nos. 1-12, November 1984-November 1985; 1984 1985 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Amusement Park Journal, Vol. 8 Nos. 1-11, December 1985-October 1986; 1985 1986 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Hersheypark: Chocolate Town U.S.A. a Pictoral History, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 19)
        This copy is signed, p. 4
      - Amusement Park Journal, Vol. 8 No. 12, November 1986 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - The Carousels of the Philadelphia Toboggan Company, Amusement Park Journal Vol. 5 No. 4, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - The Coasters of the Philadelphia Toboggan Company, Amusement Park Journal, Vol. 6 No. 1, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Amusement Park Journal, Vol. 9 Nos. 1-8, December 1986-Fall 1987; 1986 1987 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - World's Largest Ride Sensation: Flying Turns: the New Aviation Ride, Amusement Park Journal Vol. 6 No. 4, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Amusement Park Notes and Other Related Publications
        - Safety Sheet from Amusement Park Journal, June 1985 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        - Amusement Park Notes, Vol. 3, No. 3, June 1983 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        - Amusement Park Notes, Vol. 3, No. 4, October 1983 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        - Amusement Park Notes, Vol. 3, No. 5, December 1983 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        - Dorney/84, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        - Amusement Park Notes, Vol. 4, No. 2, March 1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        - Amusement Park Notes, Vol. 4, No. 1, March 1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        - Amusement Park Hotline, Vol. 1, No. 1, October 1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        - Amusement Park Journal's Park Directory / 1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        - Amusement Park Journal's Park Directory /1985 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        - Amusement Park Journal, letter from the editor on discontinuation of the publication and attatched reply from Norman D. Anderson, November 1987 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        - Advertisement for More Kennywood Memories book from Amusement Park Journal (Box 6, Folder 3)
        - Hersheypark: The Sweetness of Success advertisement from Amusement Park Journal (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Newsletters
      This subseries contains various newsletters related to the amusement and entertainment business, including information on waxworks and sideshows, as well as Dr. Anderson's own Ferris Wheel Newsletter, also referred to asFerris Wheel News.
      - Waxworks Newsletter, 1999-2008; 1999 2008 (Legalbox 9, Folder 4)
        Anderson includes a note on this file, which has been copied onto the folder. Aside from a Raleigh News and Observer article on the Art-O-Mat, this file contains copies and editions of the Waxworks International newsletter, which deals primarily with the construction and display of wax figures.
      - Sideshow Newsletter, Folder 1, 1999-2008; 1999 2008 (Legalbox 9, Folder 5)
      - Sideshow Newsletter, Folder 2, 2008-2011; 2008 2011 (Legalbox 9, Folder 6)
        A note from Anderson is reproduced on Folder 1. These newsletters were organized into one folder by Anderson and have been subsequently divided into two folders due to space constraints.
      - Amusement Business, Clippings, 1960s-1970s (Legalbox 28, Folder 2)
      - Ferris Wheel Newsletter, Issues 1-17, 1993-1994; 1993 1994 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Ferris Wheel Newsletter, Issues 18-28, 1995; 1995 1995 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Ferris Wheel Newsletter, Issues 29-45, 1996-1997; 1996 1997 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Ferris Wheel Newsletter, Issues 46-57, 1998-1999; 1998 1999 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Ferris Wheel Newsletter, Issues 58-75, 2000-2002; 2000 2002 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Ferris Wheel Newsletter, Issues 76-90, 2003-2006; 2003 2006 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Ferris Wheel Newsletter, Issues 91-100, 2007-2008; 2007 2008 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Ferris Wheel Newsletter, Issues 101-114, 2008-2009; 2008 2009 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Ferris Wheel Newsletter, Issues 115-127, 2010; 2010 2010 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Ferris Wheel Newsletter, Issues 128-140 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Ferris Wheel Newsletter, Table of Contents for Issues 1-140, 1993-2011; 1993 2011 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 144 [newsletter, pdf], 2012
        Digital content. Copies of digital files are available upon request.
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 145 [newsletter, pdf], 2012
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 146 [newsletter, pdf], 2012
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 148 [newsletter, pdf], 2012
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 149 [newsletter, pdf], 2012